<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>company &#8211; Lydford Weir</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/company/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Repairing the weir in West Lydford, Somerset</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 21:29:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Lydford Weir Company is now a registered company and charity!</title>
		<link>/2011/12/19/lydford-weir-company-is-now-a-registered-company/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[company]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lydford Weir Company is now a registered company, limited by guarantee and a registered charity, with Memorandum of Understanding and Articles of Association as required by the Charities Commission. The aims of the company are; The Lydford Lower Weir is a &#8230; <a href="/2011/12/19/lydford-weir-company-is-now-a-registered-company/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lydford Weir Company is now a <a title="Lydford Weir Company" href="http://data.companieshouse.gov.uk/doc/company/07880297" target="_blank">registered company</a>, limited by guarantee and a <a title="Lydford Weir Company (charity)" href="http://www.charitycommission.gov.uk/Showcharity/RegisterOfCharities/CharityFramework.aspx?RegisteredCharityNumber=1146817&amp;SubsidiaryNumber=0" target="_blank">registered charity</a>, with Memorandum of Understanding and Articles of Association as required by the Charities Commission.</p>
<p>The aims of the company are;</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lydford Lower Weir is a very ancient structure structure that will originally have been built to create a mill leat to proved the water source to power the mills downstream, both of which still exist, although not as working eater mills; it is mentioned n the Domesday Book.</p>
<p>As a result there is a two kilometre stretch of the River Brue upriver, in effect a level millpond, which creates a particularly delightful environment, especially for the church of St Peters which stands by the riverside that is the main place of worship for the residents of Lydford and a popular venue for weddings. This is all much appreciated not only by the local residents but also by the many visitors who come to walk beside the river and by the fishermen from Glaston Manor fishing whose principal beat this is.</p>
<p>The weir itself is adjacent to the Forest Garden, itself a registered charity, created by a local person and maintained by local residents with donations and work. The Forest Garden itself is planted with a variety of native fruit trees and hedging plants. It is much used by families for picnics in the summer. The whole ensemble, including the weir, is a haven for many kinds of wildlife, in particular kingfishers and other riverine species, including eels and voles .</p>
<p>This would all be lost if the weir collapsed, which is regarded as potentially imminent in the case of heavy weather. So the principal purpose of the charity is to maintain the beautiful environment, in the first instance by repairing the weir to ensure its long term integrity and thereafter to continue to maintain and improve the amenity surrounding it.</p></blockquote>
<p>The objects of the charity are:</p>
<blockquote><p>The conservation and improvement of Lydford weir, in Somerset, and its surrounding habitats, wildlife, flora and fauna for the benefit of the public.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
