<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lydford Weir</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Repairing the weir in West Lydford, Somerset</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 21:29:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Press Release</title>
		<link>/2012/11/06/press-release/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 19:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dodge]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Progress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=100</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[  The ancient weir on the River Brue in the village of West Lydford has just been repaired by a group of local volunteers after 3 years of fundraising.   The weir, which is the largest on the Brue, had suffered &#8230; <a href="/2012/11/06/press-release/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h5 style="text-align: center"></h5>
<h5 style="text-align: center"> <a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Weir-Press-Release.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-102" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Weir-Press-Release-300x216.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="216" /></a></h5>
<p style="text-align: left" align="center">The ancient weir on the River Brue in the village of West Lydford has just been repaired by a group of local volunteers after 3 years of fundraising.   The weir, which is the largest on the Brue, had suffered severe erosion damage in the latter part of last century and was in danger of collapse.  In September 2010, the Lydford Weir Company, a charity, was formed to effect the repair.  The target was £60,000 and funds were raised from running local events, generous personal donations from members of the local community plus a major grant from Viridor Credits Environmental Company.</p>
<p style="text-align: left">The contractor was Suttle Projects Ltd of Swanage, Dorset.   Given this summer’s very heavy rainfall, the repair was a big challenge as the river had to be diverted away from the weir and the plunge pool at the base, so that the repair work could be carried out.  This was achieved by diverting as much of the river water as possible down the associated mill streams, then pumping and syphoning the remainder of the water over the weir area, to the river bed further downstream.</p>
<p style="text-align: left">The project was completed within time and cost constraints and those who contributed to the project will be/were invited to a recommissioning reception on 18 November in the village hall, close by the weir.  A display board giving information about the weir and the repair, will be/was unveiled by local resident, Sir Conrad Heron, who undertook much of the early work into establishing ownership of the weir and the Restoration Project organisational set-up.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Latest site photos</title>
		<link>/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 22:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drkane]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Project Progress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=85</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Work on repairing the weir has now started, and can be seen in these photos. The project needs your help though &#8211; head to the donations page to contribute.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Work on repairing the weir has now started, and can be seen in these photos. The project needs your help though &#8211; head to the <a title="Donations" href="/donations/">donations</a> page to contribute.</p>

<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/002-2/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/002.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/attachment/008/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/008.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/attachment/009/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/009.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/attachment/011/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/011.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/attachment/023/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/023.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2012/09/20/latest-site-photos/attachment/027/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/027.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Somerset Rivers &#8211; West Lydford Mill Stream</title>
		<link>/2012/04/14/somerset-rivers-west-lydford-mill-stream/</link>
		<comments>/2012/04/14/somerset-rivers-west-lydford-mill-stream/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drkane]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mill stream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[somerset rivers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=69</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s some great photos of the mill stream over at Somerset Rivers.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s some <a title="Somerset Rivers - West Lydford Mill Stream" href="http://somersetrivers.org/index.php?module=mediashare&amp;func=browse&amp;aid=100&amp;mid=1513">great photos of the mill stream</a> over at Somerset Rivers.</p>
<p><a href="http://somersetrivers.org/index.php?module=mediashare&amp;func=browse&amp;aid=100&amp;mid=1500"><img class="alignnone" src="http://somersetrivers.org/mediashare/pm/sususcwbf1jn88vprbfvzy4ramikpb-pre.png" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/2012/04/14/somerset-rivers-west-lydford-mill-stream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Viridor Credits, Quarterly Reports</title>
		<link>/2012/02/07/viridor-credits-quarterly-reports/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2012 08:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viridor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=63</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No 1, February 2012 We have moved the project forward over the last three months: After bidding and bid evaluation, we have appointed Suttle Projects of Poole as the contractor. They have been to site with the Environmental Agency (EA) &#8230; <a href="/2012/02/07/viridor-credits-quarterly-reports/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>No 1, February 2012</h2>
<p>We have moved the project forward over the last three months:</p>
<ol>
<li>After bidding and bid evaluation, we have appointed <a href="http://www.suttles.co.uk/Suttle-Projects-Home.html">Suttle Projects</a> of Poole as the contractor. They have been to site with the <a href="http://www.environment-agency.gov.uk/">Environmental Agency</a> (EA) and agreed in principle the way forward. Suttle were waiting historical data on the weir from the EA, giving detailed survey data, a few weeks ago. The current plan is to undertake the physical repair works in July / August 2012.</li>
<li>Discussions are in hand with Suttle and the EA on a two stage approach to the work. Part one being enough to secure the weir, and be within the current amount of money available. Part two being additional strenghtening to prolong the life of the weir, and not have to remobilise the contractor. The decision on whether part two will go ahead will be taken as late as possible, then knowing our funding position.</li>
<li>Suttle and the EA are discussing the details of the site protection / preparation needed to minimise environmental impact during the works. There is to be a site meeting in the next couple of weeks to map out the detail of this and to initiate local action.</li>
<li>We have initiated another round of fund raising, to raise the short fall required for part two of the works. Some applications have been made and the details of others are being gathered. The local fund raising events continue, with <a href="http://charleshazlewood.com/home.html">Charles Hazlewood</a> giving his time for an event just before Christmas, this generated local press interest as well as raising over £1,000. A Burns Night was held last week. The local community members are still sending small donations by cheque. A communication giving news and saying thank you was posted in the local community areas. An all village meeting with presentation is planned for early April 2012.</li>
<li>Notification of the award by <a href="http://www.viridor-credits.co.uk/">Viridor Credits</a> gratefully received, <a href="http://www.entrust.org.uk/">ENTRUST</a> application went in, was registered and a signed copy returned.</li>
<li>The Lydford Weir Company is now <a href="http://data.companieshouse.gov.uk/doc/company/07880297">registered with companies house</a>, has its own bank account, and the application to be registered as a charity is submitted.</li>
<li>A web page; <a href="http://www.lydfordweir.org.uk/">www.lydfordweir.org.uk</a> has been created, and is being constantly updated and developed.</li>
<li>The monthly steering group meetings continue, with smaller task specific meetings occurring more frequently. It is intended that photographs of work, and monthly meeting notes, be posted on the new <a href="/">lydfordweir web site</a>. Monthly reports are given to the <a href="http://www.mendip.gov.uk/Parish.asp?id=SX9452-A7802AC6&amp;cat=7">Lydford Parish Council</a>.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weir History</title>
		<link>/2011/12/24/weir-history/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 08:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=40</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The earliest currently known records on this area are from the Anglo Saxon Chronicles; Lulla, Handmaiden to the Bishop of Glastonbury was gifted land at Lydford and elsewhere, in about 750AD. When the original weir was built across the river &#8230; <a href="/2011/12/24/weir-history/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The earliest currently known records on this area are from the Anglo Saxon Chronicles; Lulla, Handmaiden to the Bishop of Glastonbury was gifted land at Lydford and elsewhere, in about 750AD.</p>
<p>When the original weir was built across the river Brue is not yet know, but it is known that St Dunstan had work undertaken on the river, in the local area, arround 950AD.</p>
<p>The earliest currently known record of the weir and leat is in the Doomsday Book of 1086 where a mill in Lydford is recorded.</p>
<p>The current &#8216;King o Mill&#8217;, or as it was refered to at the time Kingham Mill, fed by the leat from the weir, was built arround 1600. The mill having the rights to the water flow and maintenance of this water flow.</p>
<p>In 1840 the area was owned by the Coulston Family, and Reverend Coulston rebuilt the church by the weir, the bridge just upstream of the weir and the nearby rectory, he probably also paid for the weir repair at that time.</p>
<p>In the 1930&#8217;s the Rivers Authority had the weir repaired, and after a partial collpase in the mid 1960&#8217;s they had the eastern half of the weir rebuilt, in concrete.</p>
<p>Thus it looks as though the weir needs substantial repair approximately every 50 years.</p>
<p>The Lydford community is continuing with research into the histoy of the weir and surrounding area, and more will be added to this note as it becomes available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Viridor Credits Grant</title>
		<link>/2011/12/23/viridor-grant/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 20:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fundraising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viridor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=35</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The repair project has been given a grant by Viridor Credits towards the weir repair. This will allow us to start work in 2012.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The repair project has been given a grant by Viridor Credits towards the weir repair. This will allow us to start work in 2012.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The weir in action (video)</title>
		<link>/2011/12/20/the-weir-in-action-video/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2011 18:16:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drkane]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=32</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Click to view video. ￼]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><video width="720" height="480" controls="controls"><source src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/wpid-VID_20111220_151346.mp4" type="video/mp4" /><object width="720" height="480" classid="clsid:d27cdb6e-ae6d-11cf-96b8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0"><param name="src" value="/wp-includes/js/tinymce/plugins/media/moxieplayer.swf" /><param name="flashvars" value="url=/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/wpid-VID_20111220_151346.mp4&amp;poster=/wp-admin/" /><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="true" /><embed width="720" height="480" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" src="/wp-includes/js/tinymce/plugins/media/moxieplayer.swf" flashvars="url=/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/wpid-VID_20111220_151346.mp4&amp;poster=/wp-admin/" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="true" /></object><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/wpid-VID_20111220_151346.mp4">Click to view video</a>.</video></p>
<p>￼</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lydford Weir Company is now a registered company and charity!</title>
		<link>/2011/12/19/lydford-weir-company-is-now-a-registered-company/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[company]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lydford Weir Company is now a registered company, limited by guarantee and a registered charity, with Memorandum of Understanding and Articles of Association as required by the Charities Commission. The aims of the company are; The Lydford Lower Weir is a &#8230; <a href="/2011/12/19/lydford-weir-company-is-now-a-registered-company/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lydford Weir Company is now a <a title="Lydford Weir Company" href="http://data.companieshouse.gov.uk/doc/company/07880297" target="_blank">registered company</a>, limited by guarantee and a <a title="Lydford Weir Company (charity)" href="http://www.charitycommission.gov.uk/Showcharity/RegisterOfCharities/CharityFramework.aspx?RegisteredCharityNumber=1146817&amp;SubsidiaryNumber=0" target="_blank">registered charity</a>, with Memorandum of Understanding and Articles of Association as required by the Charities Commission.</p>
<p>The aims of the company are;</p>
<blockquote><p>The Lydford Lower Weir is a very ancient structure structure that will originally have been built to create a mill leat to proved the water source to power the mills downstream, both of which still exist, although not as working eater mills; it is mentioned n the Domesday Book.</p>
<p>As a result there is a two kilometre stretch of the River Brue upriver, in effect a level millpond, which creates a particularly delightful environment, especially for the church of St Peters which stands by the riverside that is the main place of worship for the residents of Lydford and a popular venue for weddings. This is all much appreciated not only by the local residents but also by the many visitors who come to walk beside the river and by the fishermen from Glaston Manor fishing whose principal beat this is.</p>
<p>The weir itself is adjacent to the Forest Garden, itself a registered charity, created by a local person and maintained by local residents with donations and work. The Forest Garden itself is planted with a variety of native fruit trees and hedging plants. It is much used by families for picnics in the summer. The whole ensemble, including the weir, is a haven for many kinds of wildlife, in particular kingfishers and other riverine species, including eels and voles .</p>
<p>This would all be lost if the weir collapsed, which is regarded as potentially imminent in the case of heavy weather. So the principal purpose of the charity is to maintain the beautiful environment, in the first instance by repairing the weir to ensure its long term integrity and thereafter to continue to maintain and improve the amenity surrounding it.</p></blockquote>
<p>The objects of the charity are:</p>
<blockquote><p>The conservation and improvement of Lydford weir, in Somerset, and its surrounding habitats, wildlife, flora and fauna for the benefit of the public.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why does the weir need repairing?</title>
		<link>/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[peter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/001/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/001.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/002/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/002.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/005/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/005.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/006/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/006.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/014/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/014.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/021/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/021.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>
<a href='/2011/12/19/why-does-the-weir-need-repairing/attachment/032/'><img width="1" height="1" src="/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/032.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail" alt="" /></a>

]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lydford Weir repair project, monthly progress</title>
		<link>/2011/12/19/monthly-progress/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[drkane]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lydford Weir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Project Progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[report]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[September 2010; Village group present to Parish Council and Lydford Weir Repair Group is formed. October 2010; Historical search tried to access church records but these are in transit from Wells to Taunton. In negotiation with King o Mill to &#8230; <a href="/2011/12/19/monthly-progress/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>September 2010;</strong> Village group present to Parish Council and Lydford Weir Repair Group is formed.</p>
<p><strong>October 2010;</strong> Historical search tried to access church records but these are in transit from Wells to Taunton. In negotiation with King o Mill to access very old mill ownership documents.</p>
<p><span id="more-104"></span></p>
<p>Fund raisers map out a series of fund raising events in the Lydford Parish Rooms.</p>
<p>Technical group meet to map out scope of work, building on earlier study by Jacobs Gibb</p>
<p>Environment Agency (EA) contacted to define permits needed.</p>
<p>Agree to plan and delivier an All Village meeting, in November.</p>
<p><strong>November 2010;</strong> Historical search obtains agreement to view King o Mill documents.</p>
<p>Lydford Fund Raisers agree to monies from Christmas event to go into weir repair funds.</p>
<p>Technical group develop the first draft of the scope of work, method statement and risk analysis, suite of documents.</p>
<p><strong>December 2010;</strong> King o Mill documents do not show that they are the owners of the weir. Discussions on what are ownership laws for Riparian Rights owners.</p>
<p>Fund raisers detail events for first half of 2011, roughly one per month. Fund raisers discuss other sources of funds.</p>
<p>Technical group send off set of draft documents to EA for their review.</p>
<p>All Village meeting held, Parish rooms full, presentations on 4 aspects of weir repair, 100% vote to go forward.</p>
<p><strong>January 2011;</strong> Further discussions on ownership and Riparian Rights owners. Realise this is a complex area and need legal advice.</p>
<p>Fund raising events going well. Decide to investiage Viridor Credits and National Lottery Grants.</p>
<p>Letter asking for support and gifts is hand delivered to over 150 local residences and other organisations that have an interest in the weir remaining.</p>
<p>Technical group meet EA and receive constructive input to all of the documents.</p>
<p>Receive an estimate for the work from a bridge contractor who has worked in the local area, of approximately £50,000.</p>
<p><strong>February 2011;</strong> First legal review confirms that legal proof of ownership of a weir is frequently lost and can be very difficult to prove beyond doubt. Riparian law is also complex, further legal guidance sought.</p>
<p>Local fund raising progressing. Viridor Credits and Lottery contact made. discussions on the formation of a company and charity.</p>
<p>Replies to letter requesting support received from interested parties, wishing us well in our endeavours, but no donations or pledges.</p>
<p>Technical group redraft documents with EA comments included.</p>
<p><strong>March 2011;</strong> Draft scope of work or a legal opinion on Riparian Law drafted, and list of three barristers collected.</p>
<p>Local events continue to happen and others planned. Royal Wedding event, streamed live into St Peters Church followed by a &#8216;wedding buffett&#8217;, being fleshed out.</p>
<p>Technical group develop a list of works contractors.</p>
<p><strong>April 2011;</strong> Barrister scope of work agreed and sent out for quotations.</p>
<p>Scope of work etc sent out for quotations.</p>
<p><strong>May 2011;</strong> Royal Wedding event great success, giant screening of wedding, followed by a food in the Parish Rooms.</p>
<p>Agreed not to pursure Lottery fund pplication, but to focus on Viridor Credits.</p>
<p><strong>June 2011</strong>; Quotation recieved. Barrister chosen and asked to undertake work.</p>
<p>Two contractors declined to bid, two more found and invited.</p>
<p><strong>July 2011;</strong> Virodor Credits grant application completed (over 100 pages in total), and submitted.</p>
<p>Local fund raising continues.</p>
<p>Legal opinion recieved, confirming complexity. This leads to the view that Riparian Rights owners are most likely to hold the rights to the weir. Discussions held with Riparian Rights owners over repair risks and liabilities.</p>
<p><strong>August 2011;</strong> Contractor quotations recieved.</p>
<p>Agreement reached with Riparian Rights owners over repair by the Weir Repair Group.</p>
<p><strong>September 2011;</strong> Viridor Credits asked for more input from the local and wider community before they will offer support.</p>
<p>200 letters hand delivered to the local community and intersted parties, stating desperate need for the repair, and funds.</p>
<p>All contractor bids now evaluated, prefered contractor agreed upon, but commitment not made until funding is more secure.</p>
<p>Riparian Rights owners sign letters to allow community to undertake repair work.</p>
<p><strong>October 2011;</strong> Agreed Lydford Weir Company, limited by guarantee, needed, and it will be a charity</p>
<p>Monies start to come in from the Request for Support letter.</p>
<p>Charled Hazelwood offers to give a presentation to raise funds.</p>
<p>Fund Raising events continue, funds held now at over £5,000</p>
<p><strong>November 2011;</strong> In the local press, Mendip times, Western Gazette, Lydford Newsletter.</p>
<p>Receive significant donations from local residents in response to Request for Support letter. Amazing vote of confidence, in the project and community.</p>
<p>Selected contractor contacted and told of current status</p>
<p><strong>December 2011;</strong> Viridor Credits grant of £25,000 awarded.</p>
<p>Lydford Weir Company formed.</p>
<p>Charles Hazelwood event a great success, over £1,000 raised. Audience seriously stimulated by the event.</p>
<p>Lydford Christmas Revue great success.</p>
<p>Contracotr and EA visited site and start work on getting permits to work.</p>
<p><strong>January 2012;</strong> Company bank account opened.</p>
<p>Charity application forms completed and submitted.</p>
<p>Additional charity fund raising effort initiated, aiming to raise approximately £20,000 needed to complete the full scope of work, plus contingency, by mid 2012.</p>
<p>Contractor and EA review all currrent data and project that the works may be undertaken in mid 2012. With a lot of preparation work needed by all.</p>
<p><strong>February 2012;</strong> Lydford Parish Council donated over £2,500 towards the weir repair. Other local donations also recieved.</p>
<p>Local fund raising events continue to be organised, and enjoyed by the community. Burns Night was a great success.</p>
<p>Contractor and Weir Repair group meet at weir to define works for envirnmental mitigation, and clear access for works equipment.</p>
<p>Lydford Weir Company elect 3 extra directors from the lcoal community, to give more depth and diversity.</p>
<p>First quarterly project progress report given to Viridot Credits</p>
<p><strong>March 2012:</strong> The Lydford Weir Company Secretary, and Project Delivery Manager announced his relocation to Australia, so a number of changes have been made to the company and delviery team:</p>
<p>The Lydford Weir Company elected four new directors, Angela, Ted Alexander, John Long Snr, and Steve Garrett, who kindly also agreed to be the Compnay Secretary.</p>
<p>The Charity Commission came back with questions and these were positively responded to.</p>
<p>Suttle Projects came back with reviewd works and a new detailed quotation, in response to the EA&#8217;s review of the scope of work and method statement, this has a significant cost rise. More fund raising is needed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Herlpful discussions were held with the EA on ways forward, with the project and fund raising. These are all being progressed.</p>
<p><strong>April 2012;</strong> Another significant grant application is about to be submitted.</p>
<p>The Chartiy Commission has granted us charity status. <strong>Fantastic News</strong></p>
<p>Presentation to the Parish Council Annual Public Meeting on the Weir Project progress over the last 18 months, and latest position given to the Lydford on Fosse Community.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
